-== 時間軸: Meky ==-
納瓦隆島位於愛琴海中心深處。
1943年，對盟軍方面來說，它就像一根刺紮在那裡。
新近安裝在巖洞裡由雷達控制的巨炮……
……使德國最高統帥部獲得了總體戰略上的優勢。
空軍轟炸和海軍攻擊已被證明是代價巨大而無效的。
無奈之下，盟軍轉而採用滲透的方式。
9月24日夜，一支經過特殊訓練的突擊隊……
……成功潛入巨炮陣地內部……
……在巨炮底座安放了炸藥……
……然後撤離並等待英國皇家海軍軍艦的救援。
- 減速。
- 是，長官，降至半速。
開火！
快！快！
趕快！快！
快!
快，快，快，快！
條例規定，長官，當沒有燻肉、火腿，等等時……
……作為飲食供應官解決這個問題的辦法，先生……
……應該每週供應一次下水。
- 下水?
- 下水， 長官……
……比如腰子、肝、口條、腦子……
哦，該死的！
- 米勒，很高興見到你！
- 你好，長官.
- 你正忙些什麼？
- 無所事事。
我正要向延森司令官報到。
聽說你從峭壁上掉下來摔傷了。腿怎樣了？
- 至少我還能走。
- 我本以為他們會給你發養老金讓你退休。
你還在干老本行？
是的，我們已經搞到一些能讓某些場合熱鬧非凡的玩意。
我正在和一些新型雷管一起幹活，有趣極了！
對不起，長官，最好不要讓延森司令官久等。
- 晚些時候一起喝一杯。
- 他也希望一起見到你。
下士，把這放到我辦公室好嗎？
馬勒瑞。
拿把椅子。腿怎樣了？
- 還有米勒，是吧？
- 是的，長官。
聽說你加入了溫斯頓的「玩具店」？
「詭計的一部分」，白宮的那個傢伙說的。
他們對你評價很高。
是的，我們需要像你這種有特殊才能的人。
這不是一張很清晰的照片……
……但如果你能認出這個傢伙，還是會讓我吃驚的。
回想一下納瓦隆。
我實在想不起來，長官。
納瓦隆？
怎麼樣，有點印象了吧？
他怎樣？
希臘方面安德裡亞的人把他當叛徒槍斃了，是吧？
是的，我們也被告知了。
實際上，他逃走了。
他不是個叛徒。他是一個德國間諜……
……我們相信他正在南斯拉夫和當地的游擊隊在一起……
……化名是萊斯卡瓦上尉。
現在，你們兩人知道了納瓦隆方面的情況。
實際上，你們是我們所知的唯一能搞清真相的人。
所以，我想讓你們回到那裡妥善處理此事。
妥善處理，長官？
殺了他。
嚴格地說，如果可能的話。
但是，我現在是個平民，長官。
是的，我們考慮過這個。
所以，你被招回並因此而獲晉陞為……
……中士。
非常慷慨，長官。
我們怎樣去做？
你們將隸屬於第十突擊隊。
這是一個在南斯拉夫進行聯合行動的部隊的代號。
對不起，長官。這個突擊隊的任務目標是什麼？
這是保密的。
而且你不需要知道。
你不需要知道。
巴納比，進來。
- 長官？
- 上校。
第十突擊隊今晚出發。
好了，這些人歸你調遣。
對不起，請重說一遍，長官。
你只是順便捎上他們，他們是你的乘客。
僅僅搭便車而已。這是馬勒瑞少校，米勒中士。
巴納比陸軍上校。
長官，我的任務準備好了，最後的細節也計劃好了。
我們恐怕不方便捎帶乘客。
馬勒瑞少校在這方面有相當的經驗。
我當然相信。
我們要進行的可是一次危險的旅行，長官。
我們得行動迅速，我的人都很年輕，而且身體狀態良好。
- 他們已經為這次任務接受了特殊的訓練。
- 我知道這一點。
長官，我要考慮這次行動的安全性。
好了，這些傢伙有他們自己的任務。
你只要把他們安全地交到當地游擊隊的手中。
你們23：00出發去意大利……
……第二天晚上你們從那兒飛往南斯拉夫。
好的，長官。
謝謝，就這樣吧，先生們。
我們會盡最大努力不給我們自己增加麻煩，上校。
好的，這就足夠了。
- 我們正去飛機場。
- 我從巴納比上校身上感覺到……
……我們可能走水路去南斯拉夫。
對，沿著這條路走是正確的。慢一點，諾蘭。
停下。
- 諾蘭, 關燈。
- 好的，關了。
奧波斯坦，雷諾茲，鐵絲網。
少校，你要誤飛機了，除非你現在就和我們一起走。
這樣上飛機真是不同尋常，你不這樣認為嗎？
哦，是呀。萬事開頭難，對吧？
如果你在黑夜裡爬過鐵絲網，那就更不容易了……
……尤其當半英里遠處還有一扇非常漂亮的門的時候。
我們能幫什麼忙嗎？
是的，少校，你可以保持安靜，並離開那條路。
我沒有很多時間向你們解釋。
有一件事你們是不知道的……
……必須去南斯拉夫和先頭到達的3個聯絡員碰頭……
……但他們在意大利被捕了。
我們這次出發，不能讓任何人知道實情。
天啊，你看到那些傢伙了嗎？
他們正在大偷特偷。
好，制住他們。
都別亂動。
好，夥計們，上吧！
- 布萊克，在這好好照顧這個混蛋。
- 是，長官。
好了，都站住，別動。
站好，快站好！
你，站好，站好！
比爾，埃迪，把其他人抓回來。
你叫什麼名字，小子？
沃爾特。
你想怎樣？
哦，我要告訴你我不是混蛋。
沃爾特。
晚上好。
少校，走！
- 你們倆是長官？
- 或許吧。
我很樂意給你們幫忙，中士。
- 維沃.
- 哦，維沃中士，謝謝！
美軍衛生兵。
- 我說，長官！
- 都搞定了，上校。
- 把他留下嗎？
- 對。
- 奧波斯坦?
- 好的。
嗨，長官！
諾蘭在哪？
我想你可以帶上他，讓他加入我們。
好了，走！
你這個惡棍！我在那兒救了你們這些混蛋……
……而你們卻想把我扔下！
嗨，這傢伙是誰？從這滾開。
嗨，夥計，別推！別推我！
- 你看！
- 我覺得現在有點晚了。
看，你們剛才不該把我留在那兒。我救了你們。
好吧，我們不認為你會喜歡我們要去的地方。
嘿，你以為我會害怕？
那個傢伙還以為我們是去觀光呢。
是啊，那他只好等著去挨揍了。
好呀，你真是個不識時務的人！
好吧，到時候，諾蘭至少能給你個降落傘。
- 你會跳傘嗎？
- 我可以在跳的時候學。
好極了，那你就在往下掉的路上學吧。
我最好告訴上校我們有了另一個乘客。
我認為上校此時有好多事情在做，你覺得呢？
借光。
我們真應該把這個箱子扔掉。
你壓根就不知道，它可有大用場。
喂，喂，你在搞什麼？
找我的睡衣。
當然，是會劇烈爆炸的睡衣。
別擔心，老夥計。
自從這玩意「出生」之日起，我就在照顧它了。
我是一個可憐的老保姆。
我們有夥伴了。
二號引擎被擊中了！
雷諾茲，讓大伙跳傘！
跳！
走！
快呀，走！
快出去！
走呀！
快！
馬勒瑞。
好的。
- 看到其他人了嗎？
- 還沒有。低下！
走！
- 好，雷諾茲?
- 在。
米勒中士在哪兒？
老天，他怎麼會在那裡？
你們讓他上飛機了？
也許是他自己來的。
- 你在哪裡學會用飛刀的？
- 在哈佛大學，長官。
你不能稱他「長官」，應叫他「先生」，應該稱我為「長官」。
既然你在這裡，你就要服從命令。懂嗎，士兵？
是的，長官！
在德軍搜尋隊回來之前，我們必須離開這裡。
雷諾茲, 你打頭。
維沃, 殿後！
每個人都跟緊。好了，我們走。
組織力高超的年輕紳士，對吧？
- 上校，你認為我們應該向哪個方向走？
- 就是這個方向。
我們繼續往東走，就能到我們的目的地。
我們怎麼會和兩個小丑在一起？
不知道，沒辦法。英軍司令部的白癡！
快點，先生們，還沒有到喝下午茶的時間。
米勒，你認為那位年輕紳士清楚我們所在的位置嗎?
- 不，我想他不清楚。
- 我也是。
我去問問他。
好呀，你為什麼不去做呢？
打擾了，上校。
你認為我們現在在哪兒？
我知道我們在哪兒。
如果你們倆不跟緊，就不知道你們要在這裡待多久了。
好吧，咱們走吧。
- 這真是一個美麗的國家。
- 是啊，不可思議。
很像蘇格蘭高地。
- 你知道蘇格蘭嗎？
- 不知道。
當然。
我經常想總有一天我會在那裡定居下來。
看起來你不得不改變打算了。
放鬆。
歡迎。
德拉扎克上尉。
第十七游擊隊。
- 早上好，上尉！
- 歡迎，歡迎！
謝謝，德拉扎克上尉。
他們頭上纏著繃帶的樣子嚇著你們了吧？
在頭上纏上繃帶……
……德軍……你說……
……你說……我不知道怎麼給你們說。
是的，當然，挺有趣的。
你好！你好！
你好！
這是瑪麗塔，優秀的戰士。
你好，優秀的戰士。
你好，黑鬼！
也許我該把這層黑皮割下來，瑪麗塔。
住手，士兵！
我開個玩笑……
……你也和我開玩笑。
好吧，黑小子。來，我們走，和我的夥伴們一起吃飯去。
我們交朋友、喝酒，然後打德國人。
來。
來，我們走。
你在哪裡學的像那樣打人？哈佛大學嗎？
不是，在哈萊姆（哈萊姆——紐約的一個黑人聚住區）。上校？
我不想讓任何人被殺，尤其是咱們的人。
- 但那個大白癡沒安什麼好心。
- 照顧好你自己就行了，士兵。
- 今天你的腿怎樣？
- 好多了，謝謝！
好，好，看起來問題畢竟解決了，是吧？
好，或許米勒和我能將我們的演出進行下去。
我們對第十突擊隊的遭遇感到遺憾。
你們剩下的人不多了。
當然，我不知道你們的任務是什麼……
……但顯然這個任務無法完成了，上校？
他是不是很像你小時候？
你真的這麼認為？
請，來吧！
來，吃飯。
我們是塞爾維亞民族解放軍……
……不是什麼臭游擊隊。
我們像獵捕野豬一樣捕捉抵抗者！
我們和德國人共事，他們是我們的朋友！
晚上好，先生們！
施羅德少校，德國第十一集團軍。
你好，少校，見到你很高興！
我們認為那些人是游擊隊員。
- 幸虧他們不是，巴納比？
- 當然。
塞爾維亞民族解放軍？誰會相信？
你們的那三個聯絡員已經落到我們手裡……
……你們的出現讓我們更加高興。
我不感到驚訝，先生。
但是，你看，我們不是突擊隊，我們是逃亡者。
噢，逃亡者？
把他們交給我，少校，我現在就殺了他們。
你看，我們被關在特摩利的監獄裡。
我們逃了出來。
想法偷了架飛機——英國皇家空軍的蘭開斯特轟炸機，飛到這裡。
被你們的戰鬥機擊中，我們跳傘落到你們的地盤上。感謝上帝！
真有意思！
告訴我，你們為什麼逃亡？
我很高興你問這個問題。
是的。
好吧，說起來話就長了。
哦，說吧，你不必擔心我會覺得煩。
你聽說過青黴素嗎？
沒聽說。
當然，我不奇怪，那是一種新藥。
是一種能治療傷口感染的藥。
它能治療傳染病……
……包括各種社會上的流行性傳染病。
在黑市上，它是一種很搶手的緊俏貨。
我們這位朋友，維沃中士，美軍醫療特種兵……
……是我們的供貨人。
你在說你們從軍隊偷了那些藥賣給平民？
不僅僅是平民，少校，我們還賣回給軍隊。
任何軍隊。
我明白了。
告訴我，你一直盯著看的手提箱是用來幹什麼的？
哦，那個手提箱裡裝滿了青黴素。
噢，是的。或許我能看一看？
當然可以，少校。
打開箱子，米勒。
不能在這裡打開，那會把青黴素給毀掉的。
你知道任何污染都會毀壞青黴素的。
箱子必須在實驗室裡才能打開。
這些東西可是價值50萬英鎊呀！
這些我都知道，但是少校對咱們的青黴素好像很感興趣。
他只是想知道真相。
你如果不能離開這裡，你還能用那50萬英鎊嗎？
當然，可那是另外一回事，長官，我確實不能打開箱子。
看來你不相信我們的故事。
是的，不相信。
那由你決定，但他告訴你的一切都是真的。
如果你不相信，你可以去核實。
然後，你就會相信我們說的每一件事。
哦，我當然會去核實的。
核實每句話。
進去！
有趣的故事，少校，非常有趣。
現在，當他們打開手提箱後會發生什麼？
我想我們全都會得到一顆子彈。你不這樣認為嗎，上校？
總部查證了你的信息。
謝謝，鮑爾。
瑪麗塔……
……你怎麼認為？
他們在說謊。
那又有什麼關係？
殺了他們。
是呀，可能你是對的。
你知道我是怎麼想的嗎？
戰爭結束後，100萬美元！
你，一個單純的農家女孩，從哪裡來的？
我永遠都搞不清你來的那個地方。
有這麼多錢，我們能……
他們在說謊！
殺了他們。
出來！滾出來！
我告訴你什麼來著？
好啊，至少我們好好休息了一夜。
早上好，先生們！
我們的情報證實你們是從意大利逃走的。
你，還有你，跟我來，請吧。
你們從意大利逃跑是一回事……
……你們的故事以外的部分則是另一回事。
我有足夠的時間來琢磨你們所說的事。
所以，今天早上，你們知道我幹什麼了？
我打開了箱子。
瑪麗塔！
你們猜我發現了什麼？
木柴。
你期望發現什麼？在你的塞爾維亞民族解放軍
捉到我們之前，我們就把東西埋了。
我們並不笨。這是我們唯一能和你討價還價的東西。
我知道你們肯定會這麼說的，但我想你們在撒謊。
你知道他們在說謊，為什麼不讓德拉扎克幹掉他們？
冷靜點，瑪麗塔。
我不相信你們所說的青黴素存在，但也有可能真的存在。
所以，我要你們去給我挖出來。
如果我們按你說的去做，完事後你就會處死我們，
並把我們埋在同一個坑裡。
如果你們不去，我倒是當然會槍斃你們。
好了，先生們，你們只能做一個選擇。
我無法想像的是木柴怎麼會跑到箱子裡。
我也是。
我不知道應該到哪兒去找那些青黴素，你呢？
我們該怎麼辦？一直走，直到亞得裡亞海？
我認為那個冷酷的小賤貨不會讓我們走那麼遠的。
停下！
我告訴過你什麼來著？
我們已經走過你們被抓住的那個地方3英里了。
那麼，那些東西到底埋在哪兒呀？
在你們的想像中？
不，小姐，不在我們的想像中。
我想應該還在稍遠一點的地方，你覺得呢？
是的，的確，離這裡不太遠了。
那很難說，這整個地方看起來都一個模樣。
你們應該在5分鐘內開始挖。
如果我們在5分鐘內沒有找到怎麼辦？
那你們就挖自己的墓穴。
嗨，上校。
等等，這裡看起來有點眼熟。
這難道不是我們落下來時的那個窪地嗎？
是的，我想是。
我記得那邊的那個小圓丘。小姐，就是這裡。
我想就是這裡。
- 這個小圓丘這邊？
- 對。
你看，小姐，在它們之間某個地方……
在這！這不是那堆石頭嗎！
讓他們靠近，我們用鐵掀。
你對付離你最近的那兩個……
……我收拾另外兩個。
我現在想法讓他們靠近，好嗎？
當兵的，當兵的，過來！東西在這！
- 準備好了？
- 好了。
你們現在可以起來了。他們死了。
我把木柴放進了箱子裡，也藏好了炸藥。
別坐在那裡發呆了。
離開這裡，向那邊跑吧。
想辦法找到彼特維徹的游擊隊。
現在，走。
對不起，「優秀的戰士」……
……但是，對這裡發生的一切，你打算怎樣對施羅德說呢？
我自然有我自己的說法……
……可以說你們跑掉了。
在這，打我。
你們指望我毫髮無損地回去見施羅德嗎？
打我。
那麼，好吧，對不起啦。
再用力些。
走吧，上校。
我希望那個施羅德相信女孩回去對他說的話。
如果他不信，他最好仔細想想還能再相信誰？
米勒和雷諾茲怎麼辦？
他們怎麼辦，上校？
是呀。
我猜他們……
咱們走吧。
你有沒有感覺到我們被跟蹤了？
10分鐘前我就發覺了。
下一次該你假扮死屍了。
但你槍法的確不錯。
也許我不該打那麼準。
- 德國人？
- 不像，或許是德拉扎克的人，我猜。
游擊隊。感謝上帝！
早上好！
他怎麼啦？我們一直在找你們。
閉嘴。
你將向彼特維徹少校報告。
我想我們遇上了一支糟糕的隊伍，上校。
是呀，瞧那個帶頭的。
- 他怎麼樣？
- 恐怕我認識他。
- 尼古拉。
- 尼古拉是誰？
他是尼古拉·萊斯卡瓦。
我奉命殺死的那個人。
水壩。如果我沒搞錯，我知道我們在哪裡了。
是啊，我也明白了，正是我們要去的地方。
你認為他認出你了嗎？
我想是。
巴納比陸軍上校。美軍突擊隊。
馬勒瑞少校，先生。
你們從德國人那邊來的。
怎麼回事？
我們逃出來的。
萊斯卡瓦上尉有些疑慮。
如果你們是逃出來的，為什麼德國人沒追捕你們？
在我們截住你們前，我們觀察了你們5英里。
你應該觀察到我們殺了兩個跟蹤我們的塞爾維亞民族解放軍的人。
- 兩個用繃帶纏住臉的人？
- 完全正確。
不值得高興，那兩個人是游擊隊員。
是我們潛入塞爾維亞民族解放軍營地的同志……
……所以，我們潛伏在敵人那裡的特工的任務被你們破壞了，
真應該感謝你們。
對不起。
事實上我們是盟軍軍官。
我們受到這種待遇是沒有理由的。
我隸屬於第十突擊隊，我堅持得到允許……
……去聯繫盟軍聯絡官。我確信倫敦已經向你們通報了。
我們得到倫敦的很多通報……
……但很少是和實際一致的。
不論怎樣，你這回還是說對了。
關於你們的任務，我得到了通報。
就個人而言，我懷疑如果真有這麼回事……
……但是你們沒有任何裝備，是不可能完成任務的。
還有你，少校，你來這裡或許是當觀察員的吧？
不是，先生。
我有我自己的任務。
秘密任務。
機密！
有時，我有這樣的印象……
……倫敦方面看起來是把這裡的戰場……
……當成一個很隨意的搞所謂的「戰爭遊戲」的地方。
- 我可以和你單獨談談嗎？
- 你正在和我一個人說話。
- 我的意思是「單獨」談。
- 不。
在我的軍隊裡不會搞秘密勾當。
好極了，先生。
我被派到這裡找出一個代號為尼古拉的德國間諜。
我們確切地知道……
……他已經潛入人民抵抗軍內部，而且現在知道……
這個人是萊斯卡瓦上尉。
關於此人，你得到的命令是什麼？
清除他，先生。
- 清除？你是指殺了他？
- 是的，先生，是殺掉他。
你聽到了，萊斯卡瓦？
這位來自倫敦的紳士想讓我們槍斃你。
很抱歉，少校。
我必須承認你說的有些方面確實正確。
有一個代號為尼古拉的間諜……
……在這個地區南部的某些地方活動，而且也自稱萊斯卡瓦。
但是，幾個月前他被抓住，並被「清除」了。
我們已經向英國通報了。
- 但是，倫敦方面有不一樣的看法，先生。
- 是的，他們總是有不一樣的看法……
……而且經常是錯的！
馬可中尉，照顧好這些紳士們……
……讓他們就塞爾維亞民族解放軍營地的情況寫一個全面的報告。
一份特殊的報告。
上尉，我想我們應該向你道歉，不是嗎？
好了，沒關係，我們都經常接到錯誤的情報。
我們已經簡要報告過那些頭上纏著繃帶的人情況了。
用你們的人冒充他們，的確是一個很好的手法。
他們是我們在施羅德的司令部裡的特工的信使。
你們的特工就是那個小巧、黑皮膚、漂亮的……
……有著美麗的灰色眼睛和翹起的臀部的女孩？
- 你指瑪麗塔？
- 是的。
她為我們冒了很大的風險。
她是彼特維徹的女兒。
我們防守著橋的這頭。
那邊，德國人正在準備發動最後的進攻。
我們得到命令不惜一切代價阻止他們通過。
他們在那邊有多少部隊？
三個師，也許更多。我們這兒有一個旅。
很快，他們會出動坦克，然後……
- 為什麼你們不把橋炸掉？
- 我們試過幾次。
每次我們都犧牲不少戰士。
彼特維徹少校認為那樣做不明智。
好了，他那樣認為是錯的。
世上沒有炸不毀的橋。
這就是第十突擊隊來這裡的目的。
我曾經提醒過你，你沒有人手，也沒有裝備。
我可以發電報向倫敦要裝備。你只需準備一個可用的簡易機場。
哦，呼叫倫敦，為一架可能根本不會到達的飛機準備一個簡易機場。
- 你有什麼其他好的建議嗎？
- 是的。
給我20個人，我能把這橋送下地獄。
那意味著你能把我的20個人送進地獄，而不會有什麼別的結果。
這座橋是不可能被炸毀的。
請原諒，長官，你不需要20個人。
你只需要米勒。
- 米勒？
- 他是爆破專家，長官。
在英國，他可能是最優秀的。
- 這個米勒在英國？
- 不，先生。
- 他在塞爾維亞民族解放軍營地的監獄裡。
- 那他已經死了。
不一定，少校。
我不想發動一次大規模的軍事行動，上校。
我需要每一個現在已經在這裡的人，我不想他們白白送命！
先生，我們不必進行一次大規模的軍事行動。
我只需要兩個人。
這些軍官是從總部來的，他們來審訊你們。
你報告說有5個犯人，少校。
有兩個試圖逃跑，被擊斃了。
施羅德少校在軍械庫。我以前告訴過你們了……
……除了德拉扎克上尉，你們的人不能進入這個區域……
……請你們立即離開……
……如果你們認識字——我很懷疑這一點——去看一下張貼的命令。
糟糕，我的牛奶被煮糊了。
嗨，我說……
……你還是讓它糊了吧。
開門。
施羅德少校的囚犯被抓回來了。
你們看，我的同事不相信你們是逃亡者。
- 囚犯，長官。
- 什麼囚犯？
我記得你說他們被擊斃了。
好了，長官，我們可以走了嗎？
不！
這麼說可就不明智了。
快，米勒!
把他帶上。開門。
- 走。
- 馬可。
游擊隊婊子！
總是跟大鬍子好。
但他們沒有大鬍子。
和跑掉戰俘一起的那三個德國人……
……都是被人用衝鋒鎗從背後打死的。
你殺了他們。
好，把帽子給我。
開門，開門。
開門！
米勒。
維沃，別像個白癡似的站在那裡，去開車，我們該走了。
她好著嗎？
好吧，我們盡量把車開得穩一些。
喂，你，我不喜歡你對我說話的態度。
- 你說什麼？
- 我不喜歡你對我說話的態度。
除非有人告訴我到底發生了什麼，不然誰也別想走。
現在，你聽著……
你是軍官，但你耍了我兩次了。
在意大利你就想把我扔下，想背著我溜走。
你還想讓我給你們開車，但沒有人告訴我任何事。
- 你們從沒告訴我到底發生了什麼。
- 我不可能相信你。
抱歉，自從你想成為我們中的一員時，你的麻煩就開始了。
我不想成為你們那糟糕的隊伍中的一員。
我僅僅希望有相同的知情權。
我不認為你應該有什麼知情權……
……你只不過是正在被憲兵押送的一個逃兵，不是嗎？
我才不管他媽的什麼憲兵！
誰都別想走，除非有人告訴我你們的計劃。
- 我們要去炸橋。
- 炸橋？
誰的橋？那和我無關。
我們要幫助游擊隊把橋炸掉……
……如果我們運氣好，我們就能夠回家。
- 真是這麼回事？
- 就是這麼回事，中士。
- 看來這就是你們回來救米勒的原因。
- 是的，為救米勒。
你們對我沒有一丁點兒的關心。
你們只不過為了米勒回來的，而不是為我。
是的，你說對了。
你總算對我說了一次真話。
我覺得少校還說了些實在話，上校。
看來有人來找咱們的麻煩了，是吧？
那你還像白癡一樣在那站著？還不快去開車！
好吧。
好了。
得想別的辦法了。
都從車上下來。
等我的信號。
看來他真還有點用處。
- 馬可，注意警戒。
- 米勒，你還真行啊！
別逗他了，少校。
修好了嗎，中士？
是的，這個寶貝有時有點喜怒無常。
和我一樣。
關於這個萊斯卡瓦，我通過倫敦做了進一步的確認。
你覺得那個傢伙怎麼樣？
- 哪個？萊斯卡瓦？
- 對。
我還沒把他搞明白。
- 我猜也許他自己明白他在幹什麼。
- 也許吧。
沒問題吧，中士？
你怎麼想的？大概很容易就能搞定吧？
不，還說不準。
事實上，不是那麼容易。
我想說，你有點異想天開，老夥計。
- 你想告訴我什麼？
- 想看看嗎？
你開玩笑吧？我瞭解那座橋的每一英吋。
噢，是嗎？
那麼，你肯定注意到它是建在岩石上的了。
那些石墩可不是混凝土，它足有20英尺厚。
別忘了……
我告訴你，以前在倫敦已經研究過這一點。
是的，我知道你們肯定是有備而來，但是，那還不夠。
- 你什麼意思？不夠？
- 可能，你只能使它搖晃兩下而已……
……最多再讓它著點小火。
我想，除此之外，再幹不了什麼事。
我們的專家研究過這座橋，他們說可以炸毀。
我不知道你為什麼這麼說……
……但我要說的是我們的專家都是橋樑建築領域的權威人物。
當然，他們在建築方面都是專家……
……但是，在炸橋方面，我是專家。
需要8小時的時間……
……完成炸橋的整項任務。
8個小時？
這還只是假定，前提是守敵很友善，會讓我們安全撤離。
而且，他們願意用那些探照燈給我們照明。
你看到那些探照燈了嗎？我……
- 米勒。
- 長官。
我想你已經做出了很專業的說明。
多謝，長官。
如果我不是完全確定，我是不會向你們說這些的。
你一定要理解，長官，我不是在信口雌黃。
如果橋的中央支柱被……
……幾百萬噸水突然衝擊，橋會怎樣？
- 水？
我認為我們一直在談論一個錯誤的目標。
還記得我們曾經經過的那個水壩嗎？
什麼樣的水壩？在哪兒？
離這兩英里半的河的上游。
上帝！我親愛的夥計，你怎麼不早說？
哈哈，那我可就能在那個水壩上做點有意思的事了！
利用那個水壩，就可以借用大自然的力量為你工作了。
就像一個大浴缸，你要做的只是拔出那個塞子。
謝謝。
來吧，先生們。
米勒，看來那個水壩可以讓你這位爆破專家大展身手了。
讓他們準備空投場。
所以，皇家空軍空投來裝備，我們去炸掉水壩，對嗎？
對。
它就像頑石壩（頑石壩——美國科羅拉多河上的大壩）？
也許會更大些。
你怎麼知道這個，老夥計？
你們曾用這種辦法接受過空投嗎？
從來沒有。
德國人會發現的。
我們沒有更好的方法。
合乎情理。
你認為那兩個傢伙要怎樣炸掉水壩？
哦，不，我覺得他們還沒有什麼好辦法。
不過，也無所謂，維沃……
……也許有人會給他們幫忙的。
- 但願吧！
- 你好。
你要出去幹什麼嗎？外面可是很冷的。
過來坐一會兒。
謝謝，我唯一不能做的事就是「坐著」。
你不來烤會兒火？暖和一陣兒？
不，我要去看一下空投情況。
你們在那慢慢享受吧。
你看飛機會准點嗎？
簡直難以置信！
這些畜生！
這不是意外發生的。
我們失去了最後的機會。
沒有任何疑問，我們被出賣了。
聯合行動的時候，這樣的事情總是發生。
他們在拿安全問題開玩笑。
是的，這沒什麼。
我們做我們該做的，可是我們得到了什麼？
20個人死了！
- 他們中有一個……
- 那都過去了。
結束了。
最大的問題是德軍的坦克部隊就要到了……
……他們後天會通過那座橋的……
……而且沒有任何辦法能夠阻止他們。
你們四位留在這裡已經發揮不了什麼作用了。
你們將被護送回盟軍總部。
我們就這樣回去？
長官……
……我能給德國人一個噩夢般的驚喜的。
謝謝，中士。
我想我們已經得到了足夠多的驚喜了。
萊斯卡瓦上尉，安排兩個人護送這些紳士們離開。
如果能有一些裝備……
……我準能把那水壩炸上天。
真他媽讓人喪氣！
你想過沒有，德軍那裡會有我們需要的東西。
當然，他們有。
大量的高爆炸藥、地雷、雷管，所有東西。
絕對沒有任何疑問。
你們的護送人，上校。
- 他們很可靠。
- 當然，謝謝。
上尉，我認為我們需要的恐怕不是護送人。
我的中士認為德國人那裡有我們需要的裝備……
……用他們提供給我們的東西，我們會把水壩炸掉的。
那意味著你們必須潛入德軍基地。
你們中有誰會說德語嗎？
你們需要我的幫助。
謝謝，上尉。
- 這一招太棒了。
- 當然。
你看起來帥極了，你知道嗎？
是的，還是你走運，不用和我們一起去。
我們35分鐘後碰頭。好了嗎？
- 好了。
- 該德國人給我們「幫忙」了！
真可惜，學校沒有教你學會德語。
教的是拉丁語。現在學德語也不晚。
這些對你有用嗎？
沒用，我們用地雷來幹什麼？
它們看起來就像灰綠色的盤子。
也許它們比盤子要厲害的多。
我相信是。
我想知道巴納比和他的卡車發生了什麼事。
我已經問過自己同樣的問題了。
好吧，我們不能像鴨子一樣在這站著。
那邊，火車車廂，拿好東西，在那兒等他來。
巴納比現在應該在這裡的。他死到哪兒去了？
漂亮。
- 這正是我該干的活。
- 不是現在，米勒。
好了，我寧願現在組裝好，而不是躲在某條壕溝裡的時候再忙活。
- 需要多久？
- 哦，大約10分鐘……
……安靜平和的10分鐘。
這些小傢伙脾氣可是不怎麼好！
這些小「玩具」威力不大，但它們能引爆威力大的炸藥。
這麼快我們的火車就開了！
糟糕，他們這些該死的去哪裡了？
你別亂發脾氣。
你明白你是來幹什麼的？
我去四處看看，看能不能找到他們。
- 他們在那兒。
- 等等，我去叫他們。
- 那是萊斯卡瓦。
- 對。
- 馬可在哪兒?
- 我不知道……
……他們十有八九藏在那車廂裡面。
見鬼！
他在幹什麼？
一個該死的中士讓他把卡車開到那邊去了。
噢，不！
中士。
安靜點，聽我說。
有兩個英軍突擊隊員在我身後那輛帶蓬的車廂裡。
我是特別情報處的馮格裡斯萊伯上校。
站好，白癡，自然一點。
第三個是一個美軍上校……
……在你剛才打發走的那輛卡車裡。
我要把他們一網打盡。
- 萊斯卡瓦在幹什麼？
- 他正在給那個德國兵講故事吧。
去召集一隊人來抓他們。快點，安靜點！
別讓他們發覺。
然後回來向我報告。明白？
萊斯卡瓦，巴爾幹最好的吹牛專家！
好了，夥計們，我們……
哦，夥計。
我們趕快離開這裡。
- 你選了個好時間幹活呀！
- 把手提箱遞出來，好嗎？
你在耽誤時間，我們已經比計劃延遲了。
- 你怎樣過來的？
- 我用自己的辦法過來的。
幫我把東西裝好，然後放到卡車上。
- 好了，米勒?
- 對，全好了。
我們走。
拿好。
又是那個人。
我來應付他。關上門。
他們都是你的了，中士，把你的人帶過來。
可以甕中捉鱉了。
太簡單了。
愚蠢的馬可！自己想辦法逃吧！
我真不知道是怎麼回事。
該死的！我們該怎麼辦？
我的意思我們這是去哪兒？
就算去柏林我也不會覺得奇怪。
薩拉熱窩。
那是這列火車的目的地。
中途不停。
我為馬可感到難過。
謝謝。
他犧牲自己救了我們大家。
他是一個勇敢的人，也是一位好朋友。
可惜他太不小心了。
你認為那個中士認出他是游擊隊員？
我不知道。
那個中士還沒有那麼聰明。
他向你敬禮，而你穿的是下士的制服。
在德國軍隊裡，可不是規定中士向下士敬禮的。
在任何軍隊裡都不會是這樣的。
你怎麼看他向你敬禮這事，萊斯卡瓦？
也許在他眼裡我看起來像個長官。
是的，有可能。
你說這列火車開往薩拉熱窩，中途不停？
是的。
從地圖上看，一英里半後我們就會經過那個水壩。
奇怪的是，你沒有提到這一點。
那麼，這些能說明什麼？
一個愚蠢的德軍中士向我敬禮……
……還有我忘記了提我們會從水壩附近經過。
還有，你還說過馬可「自己想辦法逃吧」。
他是根本逃不出來的……
……因為他當時已經被打死了。
你出賣了什麼，萊斯卡瓦？
你猜想我是叛徒，是吧？
我不是猜想，是確信。
我早就確信無疑。
只不過我需要證據。
你是尼古拉。
你就是在希臘神秘消失的那個人。
謝謝，上校。
我做了你該做的事。
你也給我幫過忙的。
哦，上帝！
那橋看起來就像一棵聖誕樹。
5：30天就亮了。
我們大約還有一個小時的時間……
……半小時安放炸藥，20分鐘撤離。
你需要什麼，長官，來場焰火晚會？
- 這些用來幹什麼？
- 哦，我也不知道。
給我們的朋友送個見面禮吧。
噢，看在上帝的份上！放到路上，夥計，放到路上去！
哈利路亞！（哈利路亞——表示感謝、讚美上帝的意思。）
展開，拉過去。
來呀，黑鬼！
上呀，黑鬼！
來吧！
嗨，你流出的血怎麼也是紅色的，黑鬼？
這兒。
就是這兒。
你沒事吧？
快呀！見鬼！他們怎麼還沒出來？！
再給他們點時間，一會兒他們就出來了！
如果他們被抓住了，我們就會聽到警報響的。
引信定多長時間？
他們是德國人，他們是很守時的。
歷來如此。
我們沒有時間了。
20秒？
你說怎麼樣？
你決定，上校。
我在問你。
看來應該是20秒，但我們跑不了多遠。
看著橋垮倒可是夠開心的，對吧？
是的，怎麼不是呢？
一切都那麼有趣，是吧？
當然。
他們幹了些什麼狗屁事！什麼都沒發生！
混帳米勒！沒有成功！
- 它沒有……
- 什麼？
- 沒有奏效！
- 我知道沒有奏效！
- 算了，我們從這兒出去！
- 好，出去！
該死的米勒！都是他的主意！看我抓住他不掐斷他的脖子！
不會有別的了！
我們費盡千辛萬苦幹到這一步，竟然一無所獲！
的確！狗屁都沒有！
你不能指望那麼一個龐然大物能被三個小小的炸藥包給炸上天……
……你必須順其自然……
……給點時間，就會有變化的。
如果我是你，我會以最快的速度離開這裡！
- 看那些狗娘養的德國人！
- 我告訴過你，只需耐心等待那麼一會兒。
你這個可愛的混球！你真地做到了！來這兒。
你做到了！你做到了！
你這個聰明的龜兒子……你做到了！
太棒了！你這個該死的天才英國佬，我太愛你了！
小心，老夥計，克制一點。
你做到了！
米勒, 你真是一個「可惡的混蛋」……
……你知道我當時看到爆破沒有反應的時候怎麼想嗎？
你故意不告訴我，是吧？
我不想用技術細節去煩你。
我覺得那有點超過你的理解能力。
你怎麼啦？
他讓我興奮得不得了。
我們到底把那橋送下了地獄，我們贏了，
上校，我們做到了！
是的，中士，我們做到了！
就像過聖誕節一樣開心！
當然，先生們，我們幹得不錯。
但是，在……
……我們能給自己發維多利亞十字勳章……
……還有國會榮譽勳章……
……諸如此類，等等之前……
……我想我們必須先明白：第一，我們在河的另一邊。
第二，我們沒有什麼希望回到游擊隊那裡。
第三……
……很快就會有漫山遍野的德國人來找我們。
還有第四……
……我不認為我們天才的米勒中士還能……
……從他那神奇的手提箱裡給我們拿出
什麼能解決以上難題的新鮮玩意。
所以，我想我們能斷定，先生們……
……我們只能走很長的路回家去。
? anoXmous
@ http://thepiratebay.sx/user/Zen_Bud
Deep in the heart of the Aegean
lies the island of Navarone.
In 1943, it stood lik e a thorn
in the Allied side.
Newly designed radar-controlled guns
set in the heart of the ancient rock...
...gave the German High Command
total strategic dominance.
Air strik es and naval attacks
had proven costly and ineffective.
In desperation, the Allies turned
to infiltration.
On the night of September the 24th, a
specially trained commando group...
...succeeded in penetrating
the very heart of the gun complex...
...planted explosives at the base
of the giant shell hoists...
...then withdrew to await rescue
by ships of the Royal Navy.
- Reduce speed, number one.
- Aye, aye, sir. Down 50 reps.
Fire!
Move! Move!
Come on, move it!
Move it!
Move it, move it, move it, move it!
Regulations state, sir, that in the
absence of bacon, ham, et cetera...
...the acting catering officer,
that's you, sir...
...shall authorize once per week,
the issue of offal.
- Offal?
- Offal, sir...
...is kidneys, liver,
tongue, brains...
Well, I'll be damned!
- Milly, how nice to see you!
- Hello, sir.
- Whatever are you doing here?
- I've no idea.
I'm reporting to Cmdr. Jensen.
I gather you've been hurling yourself
over the white cliffs. How's the leg?
It's in the same place. I thought
they pensioned you off for good.
You still peddling
those whiz-bangs of yours?
Yes, we've got things that go boom
for all occasions.
I'm working with a new detonator.
It's interesting...
Excuse me, sir. We can't keep
Cmdr. Jensen waiting.
- We'll have a quiet pint later on.
- He'd like to see you too, together.
Corporal, put that in my office,
will you?
Mallory.
Take a pew. How's the leg?
- And Miller, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
Hear you've been attached
to Winston's toy shop.
"Department of Dirty Tricks"
as the Whitehall chaps call it.
Well, they speak very well of you.
Right. We need you chaps
for something rather special.
I'm afraid it's not exactly
a masterpiece...
...but I wonder if you can identify
this fellow.
Think back to Navarone.
I'd rather not, sir.
Nicolai?
Yes. Let you down a bit, didn't he?
But what about him?
Andrea's people had him shot
as a traitor, didn't they?
Yes, so we were told.
In fact, he escaped.
He wasn't a traitor.
He was a German agent...
...who we believe is operating now
in Yugoslavia with the Partisans...
...posing as one Capt. Lescovar.
Now, you both knew Nicolai.
In fact, you're the only people we know
of can make a positive identification.
So I'd like you to go out there
and cope.
Cope, sir?
Kill him.
Discreetly, if possible.
But I'm a civilian now, sir.
Yes, we thought about that.
So you've been recalled
to the current and promoted.
Staff sergeant.
Awfully generous, sir.
Exactly how do we get there?
We're tacking you onto Force 10.
The code name for an operation
for the Allied mission in Yugoslavia.
Excuse me, sir.
What's their objective?
It's being treated
on a need-to-know basis.
And you don't need to know.
Barnsby, come in.
- Sir?
- Colonel.
Force 10 flies out tonight.
Oh, that's all right.
Taking these boys with you.
I beg your pardon, sir?
It's a matter of transportation.
You've got passengers.
Just a sideshow.
This is Maj. Mallory, Sgt. Miller.
Lt. Col. Barnsby.
Sir, my mission is all set. It's been
planned down to the last detail.
The last thing we need are
a couple of passengers.
Maj. Mallory does have a certain
amount of experience.
I wouldn't doubt it.
We're talking about
some hard travelling, sir.
We've gotta move fast. My men
are young, in top physical shape.
- They're specially trained for this.
- I'm aware of that.
Sir, I am concerned about the safety
of my command.
Well, these chaps have got
a job to do as well.
And it's up to you to deliver them
safely to the Partisans.
And you leave for Italy
at 2300 hours...
...and you take off for Yugoslavia
the following night.
Very well, sir.
Thank you. That's all, gentlemen.
Well, we'll do our best not to make
a nuisance of ourselves, colonel.
All right, enough!
- Thought we were going to an airfield.
- From what I've observed of Barnsby...
...we might be going to Yugoslavia
by walking on water.
All right, it's right along here.
Slow down, Nolan.
Stop it.
Nolan, kill the lights.
All right, out.
Oberstein, Reynolds, the fence.
You're gonna miss your plane
unless you join us now, major.
Remarkable way of getting
on an aircraft, don't you think so?
Oh, well, nothing's ever easy, is it?
It's not easy if you insist on climbing
through fences in the dark...
...when there's a perfectly good gate
half a mile up the road.
Anything we can do to help?
Yeah, you can keep quiet
and out of the way, major.
I don't have a lot of time
for explanations.
One thing that you don't know...
...is the last three Allied missions
into Yugoslavia...
...were blown right here in Italy.
So this time when we fly out, we're
not advertising the fact to anybody.
Holy cow, will you look
at those guys!
They're stealing half the field.
All right, hold it.
Wait for me.
Okay, men, let's go!
- Blake, take care of Rastus there.
- Yes, sir.
Okay, fellas, freeze.
Back off. Come on, get back.
And you, back, back!
Bill, Eddie, fetch those other guys
out of there.
What's your name, kid?
Walter.
What's yours?
Well, it sure in the hell ain't Rastus.
Walter.
Good evening.
Major, move!
- You two guys officers?
- More or less, yes.
We're very much obliged to you,
sergeant.
- Weaver.
- Oh, Sgt. Weaver. Thank you.
U.S. Army Medical Corps.
- But, sir!
- All set, colonel.
- Still stuff outside?
- Yeah.
- Okay, Oberstein?
- Fine.
Hey, sir!
Where's Nolan?
I think you can take it
he won't be joining us.
Okay, let's go.
You son of a bitch!
I saved your asses back there...
...and you run out on me.
Hey, who is this guy?
Get out of here.
Hey, man, don't push!
Don't push me!
- Look, you!
- I think it's a bit late for that now.
Look, you just shouldn't have
left me there. I saved you bums.
Well, we didn't think you'd like
where we're going.
You let me worry about that, huh?
That guy's gonna melt
into the landscape.
Yeah, them Partisans are gonna think
they've been invaded by Zulus.
Well, you are one man short.
Well, Nolan can handle a chute,
at least.
- Can you handle a chute?
- I can learn on the job.
That's right, you learn
on the way down.
I'd better go tell the colonel
we got us another passenger.
I think the colonel's got enough on
his plate for the moment, don't you?
So sorry.
I was rather hoping we'd lost that.
You never know.
It might come in useful.
Hey, hey, what do you got in there?
My pyjamas.
Looks like high-explosive pyjamas
to me.
Not to worry, old boy.
Been handling this since I blew up
the nursery with my first chemistry set.
Poor old nanny.
We got company.
Cut two!
Reynolds, bail out!
Jump!
Go!
Come on, move it!
Come on, get out!
Come on, move!
Come on!
Mallory.
Okay.
- Seen any of the others?
- Not yet. Get down!
Come on.
- Okay, Reynolds?
- Yeah.
Where's your Sgt. Miller?
How the hell did he get here?
You let him on the plane?
I think he more or less
invited himself.
- Where did you learn to use a knife?
- Harvard University, man.
You don't call him man.
You call him sir, and you call me sir.
And as long as you're here, you do
as you're told. Understood, soldier?
Yes, sir.
We've gotta get out of here
before that patrol comes back.
Lt. Reynolds, take point.
Sgt. Weaver, bring up the rear.
And everybody keep up.
All right, let's go.
Organized young gentleman,
isn't he?
- Any idea where we are, colonel?
- Not a hell of a lot, no.
If we keep going east, we'll
end up where we're supposed to.
How did we get stuck
with those two clowns?
I don't know, Doug.
Some idiot at British HQ.
Come along, gentlemen.
It's not teatime yet.
Do you think that young man has
any idea where we are, Milly?
- No, I shouldn't think so.
- I shouldn't think so, either.
I'll go and try and find out.
Yes, why don't you do that.
Excuse me, colonel.
Do you have any idea
where we are?
I've got a good idea where we are.
And how long it's gonna take to get
there, if you two can't keep up.
All right, let's move it.
- This is really beautiful country.
- Yes, marvellous.
Rather like the Scottish Highlands.
- Do you know Scotland?
- No.
Yes.
I've often thought that I'd rather like
to settle down there some day.
Looks like you're gonna have
to change your plans.
Take it easy.
Welcome.
Capt. Drazak.
Seventeenth Partisan Regiment.
- Good morning, captain.
- Welcome, welcome!
Thank you, Capt. Drazak.
They frightened you with bandages,
huh?
Without bandages you...
German, how you say:
You say, "flamethrower."
Yeah, yeah, flamethrower.
Hello! Hello!
How do you do?
This is Maritza,
good soldier comrade.
How do you do,
good soldier comrade?
Hello, blackie.
Maybe it comes off now, Maritza.
Back off, soldier.
I make big joke...
...but joke on me.
Good, blackie. Come, we go.
We eat with our comrades.
We make friends and drink.
Then we fight the Germans.
Come.
Come, we go.
Where did you learn to punch
like that? Harvard?
No, Harlem. Colonel?
I'm not trying to get anybody
killed, least of all me.
- But that big idiot back there started it.
- Just watch yourself, soldier.
- How's the leg today?
- It's much better, thank you.
Good, good. Well, it looks like
things may work out after all, huh?
Well, perhaps Miller and I can still
carry out our little sideshow.
Sorry about Force 10.
You're down to two men, aren't you?
Of course, I don't know
what your mission was...
...but obviously it just isn't
on now, is it, colonel?
Looks rather like your own youngster,
doesn't he?
Do you really think so?
Please, come.
Come, eat.
We are Chetniks...
...not stinking Partisans.
We hunt Allied commandos
like wild pigs!
We work with Germans.
They are our friends!
Good evening, gentlemen.
Maj. Schroeder, 11 th army corps.
How do you do, major?
Delighted to meet you.
We thought these people were
Partisans.
- Of all the luck, eh, Barnsby?
- Sure.
Chetniks? Who would have
believed that?
The other three Allied missions
that fell into our hands...
...were not quite so happy about it
as you appear to be.
I'm not surprised, sir.
But, you see, we're not commandos.
We're deserters.
Deserters?
Give them to me, major.
We kill them now.
You see, we were
in a prison camp in Termoli.
We escaped.
Managed to steal a plane.
Flew here, RAF Lancaster.
Were attacked, hit, bailed out and
landed in your territory, thank God.
Fascinating.
Tell me, why exactly
did you desert?
Now, I'm glad you asked that.
Yes.
Well, I am afraid
that is rather a long story.
Oh, please, you must not
be afraid of boring me.
Have you ever heard of penicillin?
No.
Well, I'm not surprised.
It's new.
It's a drug that prevents wounds
from becoming infected.
It cures a whole range of infections...
...including some of the nastier
social diseases.
It's become one of the most
sought-after items on the black market.
Our friend here, Sgt. Weaver
of the American Medical Corps...
...was our supplier.
You are saying you stole these drugs
from the Army to sell to civilians?
Not just to civilians, major.
We'd sell it back to the Army.
Any army.
I see.
Tell me, what has all this to do
with that suitcase you keep looking at?
Well, that suitcase
is full of our penicillin.
Oh, indeed. Perhaps
I could see some of it?
Certainly, major.
Open it, Miller.
You can't do that here,
you'd ruin the lot.
You know perfectly well that
any contamination will destroy it.
It must be opened
under laboratory conditions.
There's nearly half a million
pounds worth of stuff here.
I know all that, but the major
is not interested in our penicillin.
He only wants to know the truth.
What's the use of a half a million
pounds to you out here?
Yes, well, that's beside the point,
sir, but I'm not going to open it.
Our story doesn't seem
to convince you.
No, it does not.
That's up to you, but every word
he's told you is true.
If you don't believe it,
check with your intelligence.
They'll verify the entire story.
Oh, I shall certainly verify
your story.
Every word of it.
Get in!
Cute story, major, very cute.
Now, what happens
when they open the suitcase?
I should think we'll all get shot.
Don't you, colonel?
Headquarters acknowledges
your signal.
Thank you, Bauer.
Maritza...
...what do you think?
They're lying.
What does it matter, anyway?
Kill them.
Yeah, you are probably right.
Do you know what I was thinking?
After the war, $1 million.
You, a simple peasant girl
from where?
I can never pronounce the name
of the place you come from.
With so much money, we could...
They're lying.
Kill them.
Out! Get out.
What did I tell you?
Well, at least we got
a good night's sleep.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Our intelligence confirms
your escape from Italy.
You and you, follow me, please.
Your escape from Italy
is one thing.
The rest of your story
is something else.
I had time to sleep on it.
So this morning,
you know what I did?
I opened the suitcase.
Maritza!
And what do you think I found?
Firewood.
What did you expect? We buried it
before your Chetniks picked us up.
We're not stupid. It's the only thing
we've got to bargain with.
That is what I thought you would say.
I think you're lying.
You know they're lying. Why don't
you let Drazak get rid of them?
Gently, Maritza.
I don't believe your so-called penicillin
exists, but it just might.
So I will let you go
and dig it up for me.
And if we do, you'll shoot us
and bury us in the same hole.
I shall certainly shoot you
if you don't.
Well, gentlemen,
the choice is yours.
What I can't figure is how
the firewood got in the case.
Neither can I.
Don't know where we're going to find
any spare penicillin here, do you?
What are we going to do, keep
walking until we reach the Adriatic?
I don't think the iron maiden
will let us get that far.
Halt!
What did I tell you?
We are three miles past the spot
where you were picked up.
Well, where is this
wonderful treasure?
In your imagination?
No, ma'am,
it's not in our imagination.
I think it's a bit further on,
don't you?
Yes, it is. Well, I mean,
it's not much further than this.
It's hard to tell,
the whole country looks alike.
You will start digging
within five minutes.
What if we haven't found it
in five minutes?
Then you will be digging
your graves.
Hey, colonel.
Wait a minute,
now this looks familiar.
Isn't this our little hollow
down here?
Yes, I think it is.
I remember this knoll over here.
Ma'am, this is it.
I think this is it.
- This knoll over here?
- Right.
You see, comrade, we lined it up
between them...
There you are!
There's our pile of stones.
Gotta get them closer
and we use the spades.
You take the two
that are closest to you...
...and I'll take the other one
and the broad.
I'm gonna get them
closer now, okay?
Fritz. Fritz, come!
It's here.
- Ready?
- All right.
You can get up now.
They're dead.
I put firewood in people's cases
and hide their high explosives.
Don't sit there gawping.
Get out of here.
Keep moving in that direction.
Try to find Petrovitch's Partisans.
Now, go.
Excuse me,
good comrade soldier...
...but exactly what story are you
gonna tell Schroeder about all this?
You took us by surprise.
You got away.
Here, hit me.
Did you expect me to go back there
with my hair combed?
Hit me!
Well, all right. I'm sorry.
Harder!
Come on, colonel.
I hope that man Schroeder
believes that girl's story.
If he doesn't believe her, he'd better
think twice about calling her a liar.
What about Miller and Reynolds?
What about them, colonel?
Yes.
I suppose they...
Let's move it.
Do you have the feeling
we're being followed?
About the last 10 minutes.
Next time you can play the corpse.
Yeah, you seem pretty good
with that thing, though.
Could have been luck.
- Germans?
- Yes, or Drazak, I suppose.
Partisans, thank God!
Good morning.
What's the matter with him?
We've been looking for you.
Be quiet.
You will make your report
to Maj. Petrovitch.
I think we've run into
bad company, colonel.
Yes, the leader.
- What about him?
- Afraid I know him.
- Nicolai.
- Who the hell is Nicolai?
It's Nicolai Lescovar.
The man I was sent to kill.
Dam, if it's the one I think it is.
I know where we are.
So do I. Right in it.
Do you think he's recognized you?
Yes, I think so.
Lt. Col. Barnsby,
United States Rangers.
Maj. Mallory, sir.
You got away from the Germans.
How?
We escaped.
Capt. Lescovar
has his doubts about that.
If you escaped, why were
the Germans not pursuing you?
We observed you for five miles
before we picked you up.
You should've observed that we killed
two Chetniks that were following us.
- The men with the bandaged faces.
- Exactly.
Hardly a cause for congratulation.
Those two men were Partisans.
Comrades of ours whom we had
infiltrated into the Chetnik camp...
...so now all links with our agent there
are broken, thanks to you.
I'm sorry.
The fact remains
that we're Allied officers.
There's no reason
we should be treated this way.
I'm in command of Force 10.
I insist that we be allowed...
...to contact the Allied mission.
I'm sure London informed you.
We are informed
of many things by London...
...very few of them
ever seem to materialize.
However, you are right.
I was informed of your mission.
Personally, I doubt if it was
ever a practical one...
...but now that you are here without
equipment, the question is academic.
And you, major, you came here
as an observer, perhaps?
No, sir.
I was charged with a mission
of my own.
It's confidential.
Confidential!
Sometimes I get the impression...
...that London looks
on this theatre of operations...
...as a convenient place for conducting
what they call "war games."
- May I speak to you personally?
- You are speaking to me personally.
- I mean alone.
- No.
The People's Army does not conduct
military business in secret.
Very well, sir.
I was sent here to identify a German
agent, code name Nicolai.
We are reliably informed...
...that he has infiltrated the People's
Resistance Army, and is now known...
...as Capt. Lescovar.
And having identified this man,
what were your further orders?
I was to eliminate him, sir.
- Eliminate. Don't you mean kill?
- Yes, sir. I do mean kill.
Do you hear that, Lescovar?
The gentlemen from London
want us to shoot you.
I'm sorry, major.
I must admit you are
indeed partly right.
There was an agent
named Nicolai...
...operating somewhere south of here
and also calling himself Lescovar.
But he was identified many
months ago. And eliminated.
The British were informed.
- But London were very specific, sir.
- Yes, they frequently are specific...
...and just as frequently wrong!
Lt. Marko,
see that these gentlemen...
...give you a full report on their
activities in the Chetnik camp.
A specific report.
Well, captain, I guess we owe you
a bit of an apology, don't we?
Well, it happens. We all
get badly briefed sometimes.
Wish we had been briefed
about the men with the bandages.
Replaced them with a couple
of your own, that's a good trick.
They were messengers to our agent
at Schroeder's headquarters.
Is your agent small, dark, pretty...
...beautiful grey eyes
and shoots from the hip?
You mean Maritza?
Yes.
She took a big chance for us.
She isn't Petrovitch's daughter
for nothing.
We hold this end of the bridge.
Over there, the Germans
prepare for the final attack.
We have been ordered to prevent
them crossing at all costs.
What exactly do they have
over there?
Three divisions, perhaps more.
We hold a brigade here.
Soon they will bring up tanks, then...
- Why haven't you blown the bridge?
- We have tried several times.
Each time we lost valuable men.
Maj. Petrovitch has decided
it is impractical.
Well, he's wrong about that.
There's no bridge in the world
that can't be blown.
That's what Force 10
was here to prove.
I told you before, you have no men,
you have no equipment.
I can radio London for equipment.
Get me an airstrip operational.
Oh, call London, prepare an airstrip
for a plane that may never arrive.
- Have you anything else to suggest?
- Yes.
Give me 20 men,
I can blow that bridge to hell.
You mean you can blow 20
of my men to hell, for nothing!
That bridge is indestructible.
Excuse me, sir,
you don't need 20 men.
You need Miller.
- Miller?
- He's an expert with explosives, sir.
He's probably the best in England.
- This Miller is in England?
- No, sir.
- Prisoner in the Chetnik camp.
- Then he's already dead.
Not necessarily, major.
I refuse to mount a full-scale operation
just to find out, colonel.
I need every single man
I've got here, now!
Sir, we don't need to mount
a full-scale operation.
Just give us two men.
These officers are from headquarters.
They're here to interrogate you.
You reported five prisoners, major.
Two of them tried to escape.
They were shot.
Maj. Schroeder is in the armoury,
and I have told you before...
...this area is out of bounds
to you people, except Capt. Drazak.
Kindly remove yourselves
immediately...
...and if you can read, which I doubt,
take a look at standing orders.
There. You have made me
burn the milk.
So I did.
Let it burn.
Open up.
Prisoners for Maj. Schroeder.
You see, my colleague does not
believe you are deserters.
- The prisoners, sir.
- What prisoners?
I thought you said these men
had been shot.
Right, gentlemen, shall we go?
No!
This is not correct.
Quick. Miller!
Bring him. Open it.
- Go.
- Marko.
Partisan bitch!
Always so kind to the men
with burns.
But they have no burns.
The three Germans
with the prisoners that escaped...
...all shot in the back
with machine pistols.
You killed them.
Good. Give me the hat.
Open. Open up.
Open!
Milly.
Weaver, don't stand there like
an idiot. Let's get this truck moving.
She okay?
Well, we'll drive as carefully
as we can.
Hey, you.
I don't like the way you talk.
- You what?
- I don't like the way you talk to me.
This truck doesn't move till somebody
tells me what's going on.
Now, look, you...
You bigtime officers
have shafted me twice.
You tried to dump me in Italy,
ran out on me back there.
You expect me to drive you like some
chauffeur. Nobody tells me anything.
- You don't tell me what's going on.
- I don't believe this.
Excuse me, but is your trouble
that you want to be part of the team?
I don't want to be a part
of any lousy team.
I just want some equal consideration.
I don't think you'll get
equal consideration...
...from those people back there.
Do you?
I don't care if they're
the U.S. Cavalry.
Nobody moves until somebody
tells me what you're planning to do.
- We're going to blow up a bridge.
- A bridge?
Whose bridge?
Not me, I'm blowing up nothing.
We are going to help the Partisans
blow up a bridge...
...and then if we're very lucky,
we can all go home.
- Is that a fact?
- That's the general idea, sergeant.
- That's why we came back for Miller.
- Yeah, Miller.
You didn't give a mother-hunch
about me.
You came back for Miller,
but you didn't come for me?
No, we didn't.
That's the first straight answer
you've given me.
I think the major's
got a point, colonel.
They do look kind of mean,
don't they?
Don't stand there gaping like an idiot.
Get in there and drive the truck!
All right.
We'll have to do this another way.
Get away from the truck.
Wait for my signal.
Useful little insect, isn't he?
- Keep an eye on him, Marko.
- Miller, you are an incurable showoff.
Don't knock it, major. Don't knock it.
So now it works, huh, sergeant?
Well, these babies are
a little temperamental sometimes.
Like me.
Lescovar's confirmed my signals
got through to London.
Do you like that chap?
- Who's that, Lescovar?
- Yeah.
I haven't thought anything
about him.
- Knows his job, I suppose.
- Yes, he does, doesn't he?
All right, sergeant?
What do you think?
Pretty straightforward, isn't it?
Well, no, not exactly.
In fact, not by a long chalk.
I'd say you're flogging
a dead horse there, old man.
- What are you trying to tell me?
- Want to take a look?
Are you kidding?
I know every inch of that bridge.
Oh, yeah?
In that case, you'll have noticed
how it's built into the living rock.
And how those main pilings are not
just concrete, but 20 feet thick.
That's not forgetting...
I told you, London's dropping
the same stuff we had before.
Yes, I know what you're getting,
but it's not gonna be enough.
- What do you mean, not enough?
- You might just bend it a little...
...burn the paint work
here and there.
But nothing that would seriously
inconvenience the Jerries, I thought.
Our experts have been studying
that bridge, and they say it'll blow.
I don't know where you learned...
...but I'm talking about
the best engineers in the business.
Yes. They're probably experts
at building things...
...whereas I'm an expert
at blowing them up.
Take it from me that
one would need eight hours...
...to make a decent job
of that bridge.
Eight hours?
Assuming, of course, the Jerries are
kind enough to leave us in peace.
And maybe provide
a few working lights.
You've seen those searchlights,
have you? Well, l...
- Miller.
- Sir.
I think you've made
your technical point.
Many thanks, sir.
If I weren't absolutely sure of my facts,
I wouldn't be telling you this now.
And you do understand, sir,
I'm not exaggerating.
What would happen to the bridge
if that central arch...
...was suddenly hit
by several million tons of water?
- Water?
I think we've been talking
about the wrong target.
Remember that dam we passed
up around the bend?
What kind of a dam?
Where is it?
Two and a half miles
up the river.
But, my dear chap,
why didn't you say so before?
Oh, I could do a tremendous job
on a dam, yes.
With a dam you've got natural
elements working for you.
It's like an enormous bath.
All you've got to do is pull the plug.
Thank you.
Come along, gentlemen.
As a technician, I thought you might
be interested in that dam, Milly.
Get them outside
for the dropping zone.
So the RAF drops the stuff
and we blow the dam, right?
Right.
Is it anything like Boulder Dam?
Now, that baby's big, man.
Wouldn't know, old boy.
How often have you used this
as a dropping zone?
Never.
The Germans see to that.
We have to keep moving around.
Makes sense.
You think those two guys know
anything about blowing a dam?
Oh, no, I shouldn't think
they've got a clue.
But never mind, old Weaver...
...we sergeants will see them through
as usual.
- Right.
- Hello.
Ought you to be out and about?
It's jolly cold.
Come on in, take a seat.
Thank you, but one thing
I cannot do just yet is sit down.
You're not staying for the fireworks?
Bags of panic and blue lights.
No. I've seen too many airdrops.
They don't compare
to a nice, warm bed.
Would you believe it?
Right on time.
I don't believe it.
Poor bastards.
This was no accident.
We've lost our last chance.
There is no question.
We were betrayed.
Aren't we always
with Allied missions?
Their security's a joke.
It doesn't matter.
We do our part,
and what do we get?
Twenty lives lost.
- One of them...
- It's past.
Finished.
All that matters now is that the
Germans are marshalling their tanks.
They will cross the bridge
tomorrow...
...and there is nothing
we can do to stop them.
And you four gentlemen have
outstayed your usefulness.
You will be escorted back
to the Allied military mission.
Out of harm's way?
Sir...
...I could leave the Germans
some very nasty surprises.
Thank you, sergeant.
I think we have had
enough surprises.
Capt. Lescovar, see that these
gentlemen have an escort of two men.
If those chaps had just half
the equipment of the Jerries...
...I could've made that dam
look like a Swiss cheese.
It's absolutely sickening.
Do you think the Jerries will have that
gear we need in their supply dump?
Of course they would.
Lashings of HE, land mines,
detonators, everything.
It's an absolute certainty.
Your escort, colonel.
- I think you will find them reliable.
- Okay, thank you.
I think we're going to need
rather more men than this, captain.
My sergeant thinks that the Germans
have the necessary equipment...
...in their forward supply dump
so that the colonel can blow the dam.
That means you'd have to get
into the marshalling yards at Mostar.
None of you speak enough German.
You need me to help.
Thank you, captain.
- You know, I could get shot for this.
- Couldn't we all?
You look real beautiful,
you know that?
Yes, it's all right for you.
You don't have to come with us.
We'll be back in exactly
35 minutes, right?
- Okay.
- That's if the shop's open, old boy.
Pity they didn't teach you German
at that school of yours.
Instead of Latin?
Perish the thought, old boy.
These any use to you?
No, tellermines is what we want.
They look like dirty
grey-green dinner plates.
Maybe they just haven't got any.
They have.
I wonder what happened
to Barnsby and his truck.
I've been asking myself
the same question.
Well, we can't just stand here
like ducks in thunder.
Over there. The railway wagon.
Get the stuff in there till he comes.
Barnsby should have been here
by now. Where the hell is he?
Beautiful.
- They're just the job.
- Not now, Milly.
Well, I'd rather do it now
than in some ditch.
- How long?
- Oh, about 10 minutes...
...given peace and quiet.
These little sods
can be temperamental.
The gubbins itself is harmless enough
but aren't we all, until detonated.
For a moment
I thought we were off.
Hey, where in the hell
have they gotten to?
You maniac.
What the hell are you doing here?
I'll go and have a look around,
see if I can find them.
- There he is.
- Wait. I'll get him.
- That's Lescovar.
- Yeah.
- Where's Marko?
- I don't know...
...but ten to one they're hiding
in that boxcar.
Bloody hell.
What's up now?
Some great ape of a sergeant,
he's sent Barnsby's truck away.
Oh, no.
Sergeant.
Be quiet. Listen to me.
There are two British commanders
in that cattle truck behind me.
I'm Col. Von Ingorslebon,
Special Field Intelligence Group.
Stand still, idiot. Look natural.
There is a third,
an American colonel...
...in the truck which you
just sent away.
I want to take them all together.
- What's Lescovar doing?
- He's shooting him some kind of story.
Go and assemble a squad
of armed men. Quickly and quietly.
And keep them out of sight.
Then report back to me.
Understand?
Good old Lescovar.
Best line-shooter in the Balkans.
All right, you guys, let's...
Oh, man.
The sacks, get them up here quick.
- You picked a fine time to do this.
- Sling out my suitcase, will you?
You trying to screw up this operation?
We're behind schedule already.
- How did you get here?
- I've been through that already.
Help me get this stuff loaded
and get it on the truck.
- Right, Miller?
- Right, all set.
Let's go. Easy.
Hold it.
It's that man again.
I'll take care of him. Close the door.
They are all yours, sergeant.
Bring the squad.
All clear?
Give them a moment
to get out of sight.
That fool, Marko,
must have given himself away.
I don't know how.
How in the hell are we gonna
get back across the river?
I mean, where are we going?
Berlin, I shouldn't wonder.
Sarajevo.
That's where the train goes.
No stops.
I'm sorry about Marko.
Thank you.
It's a risk we all take.
He was a brave man
and a good friend.
Pity he got careless.
Do you think that big sergeant
spotted him as a Partisan?
I can't buy that.
The sergeant wasn't that bright.
He saluted you,
you're wearing a corporal's uniform.
That doesn't rate a salute
in the German army.
Not in anybody's army.
Why do you think
he saluted you, Lescovar?
Perhaps he recognized
my natural superiority.
Yes, perhaps.
You say this train goes
to Sarajevo, no stops?
Yeah.
But I noticed on the map that we pass
within a half a mile of the dam.
Strange you didn't bother
to mention that.
Now, what's all this about?
Some fool of a sergeant salutes me...
...and I forget to mention
that we pass near the dam.
And a little while ago, you said that
Marko must have given himself away.
I don't think he gave anything away...
...except his life.
What did you give away, Lescovar?
You think I'm a traitor, is that it?
I don't think, I know.
I've always known.
I just couldn't prove it.
You're Nicolai.
You're the man who
blew us in Greece.
Thank you, colonel.
I've done your job.
You help me do mine.
Oh, crikey.
It's lit like a Christmas tree.
Dawn's around 5:30.
Gives us an hour to get in...
...half-hour to set the charges
and 20 minutes to get clear.
What you need, sir,
is a little diversion, isn't it?
- What am I supposed to do with this?
- Oh, I don't know.
Try and imagine you're a dog.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
On the road, man, on the road!
Hallelujah!
Just unroll it and string it out.
Come on, blackie.
Come on.
Hey. You bleed red blood,
eh, blackie?
Here.
Right here.
You all right?
Come on, blow, damn it! Blow!
Give them a chance.
They'll be here in a minute.
If they'd been caught,
we'd have heard the alarm go off.
How long do we make the fuse?
They're Germans,
they're gonna be punctual.
Usually are.
We've run out of time.
Twenty seconds?
What do you say?
It's your decision, colonel.
I'm asking you.
Twenty seconds sounds about right,
then we won't have so far to run.
It would have been nice
to see that bridge go, huh?
Yes, wouldn't it?
All been very interesting,
though, hasn't it?
Yes.
It didn't do a goddamn thing! Nothing!
Miller! That useless git!
- It didn't...
- What?
- It didn't work!
- I know it didn't work!
- Well, let's get out of here!
- Yeah, let's get out of here.
When I catch that little perisher,
I'll wring his useless neck!
Nothing!
We've been through
all this, and nothing!
Nothing but:
You can't expect an enormous volcano
with three tiny bags of explosives.
You have to let nature take her course.
Give it time, it'll work.
If I were you, I'd get out of here fast!
- You son of a bitch!
- I told you, it's only a matter of waiting.
You cute little son of a bitch!
You did it! Come here.
You did it! You did it!
You cute little son of a... You did it!
Why, you limey genius, I love you!
Steady on, old Weaver, steady on.
You did it!
Miller, you horrible little man...
...you knew that was gonna be
a slow-motion explosion.
You deliberately didn't tell me,
did you?
I didn't want to bore you
with technical detail.
I thought it might be
a bit over your head.
What happened to you?
He bit me in all the excitement.
But damn it to hell, we did it,
colonel, we did it!
Yes, we did, sergeant. We did!
And a merry Christmas.
Yes, gentlemen, we did it.
But before...
...we can start awarding ourselves
Victoria Crosses...
...and Congressional Medals of Honor
and so on...
...and so forth and such like...
...I think I'd better point out that, one:
We're on the wrong side of the river.
That two: We have no hope
whatsoever of rejoining the Partisans.
And that three:
This neck of the woods will soon be
crawling with bad-tempered Germans.
And four:
I don't think that our little genius,
Sgt. Miller there...
...has even got a box of matches
left in his suitcase.
And so, therefore,
I think we can take it, gentlemen...
...that we are going to have
a very long walk home.